(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-03T21:00:57.843260",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
パレード パレード パレード 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's shining bright
呼び合う声を 合図に
With our calling voices as the signal
パレード パレード パレード 探しに行く
Parade, parade, parade! Searching for it
スタートは 何度だって
No matter how many times we start over
イェーイ！
Yay!
皆さんこんにちは！儒烏風亭らでん生誕祭2025始まりました！
Hello everyone! Jyufuutei Raden Birthday Festival 2025 has begun!
盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's get hyped!
ただ 独り言 呟いた
I just muttered to myself
ただ 始まりたくて 走った
I just ran because I wanted to begin
遠く 暗がりに灯った
Far away, a light flickered in the darkness
それは 眩しすぎた名前
That name was far too dazzling
それは 優しすぎる思い出きっと
That memory was far too kind
近づけと 手を伸ばした
I reached out my hand to get closer
思いがけず 結び合った
Unexpectedly, we became bound together
ほら 今 迷子は “僕等” になった
Look, now the lost ones have become "us"
パレード パレード パレード 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's shining bright
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいで
Bring along both your regrets and your love
風 夢 羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, and wings—we can take flight
ささやかな祈りは 光 終わりなし 兆し
Our quiet prayers are an endless light, an omen
君を見つけたこと 胸を張れるよ
I can hold my head high knowing I found you
さあ これからは
Now, from here on,
アワブライト パレード パレード！
our bright parade, parade!
ただ 頼りない予感を
With such unreliable premonitions,
歌を 恥ずかしかなんてないよ
there's nothing to be ashamed of singing.
誰も溶けない イマジナリー
An imaginary no one can untangle,
いつか また逢える おまじない
a spell so we can meet again someday.
あの日 ゼロに始まった ストーリー
The story that began at zero on that day.
数えきれないことの数えるような思い出じゃないさ
It's not just memories you can count on two hands,
ほら 今 僕らを一つと呼ぼう
Look, now let's call us as one.
パレード パレード パレード！ 美しいんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's so beautiful.
許し合える刹那
Moments of forgiveness,
夜はきらめく
the night sparkles.
雨、晴れ、カレイド またとない空
Rain or shine, a kaleidoscopic, one-of-a-kind sky.
相応しい旅路とは
A fitting journey
君と在る事さ
is simply being here with you.
君と在る事なんだ
Yes, it's being here with you.
「ただいま」を聞けば
When I hear "I'm home,"
「おかえり」って叫ぶよ
I shout out "Welcome back!"
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't that how it should be?
パレード パレード パレード！ 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! We're gonna shine!
暗がりを映し出すのは君だ
What brings out the darkness is you.
パレード パレード パレード！ 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! We're gonna shine!
悔しさも愛しさも連れておいで
Bring along your regrets and your love, too!
風、夢、羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, wings—you can take flight!
ささやかな祈りは光 終わりなき兆し
These quiet prayers become light, an endless omen.
君と飛び込んでいく すべきスタートさ
Diving in with you, this is the proper start!
ここから これから
From here, from now on,
アワブライト パレード パレード！
our bright parade, parade!
Our bright parade, parade!
はい、ということで 始まりました！十風亭らでん生誕祭2025です！皆さん 楽しんでますかー！
Yes, and with that, Juufuutei Raden's Birthday Festival 2025 has begun! Are you all having fun?!
どうもホロライブデバイスReGLOSSのね、秘密結社ネクロマンサー担当、十風亭一門の前座みたいな、十風亭らでんでございます！こんばんはー！
Hello, I'm Juufuutei Raden, the opening act of the Juufuutei family, from hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS! Good evening!
本日は2月4日、私十風亭らでんの誕生日ということで、誕生日を記念して、初めての生誕ライブ、やります！やったー！
Today, February 4th, is my birthday as Juufuutei Raden, so to celebrate, I'm holding my very first birthday live! Yay!
十風亭らでん生誕祭2025、ここで出会ったのも何かのご縁ということで、今日のタグは、
Juufuutei Raden Birthday Festival 2025. Since meeting here is some kind of fate, today's hashtag is...
#らでん生誕祭2025、#らでん生誕祭2025です！一杯ポストしてくれると嬉しいです！
...#RadenBirthday2025! I'd be happy if you post a ton!
あの十風亭らでんの十風亭が一発変換で出ないので、あの、シンプルに、らでん生誕祭2025です。よろしくお願いします！
Also, 'Juufuutei' doesn't convert in one go, so simply put, it's #RadenBirthday2025. Please support me!
さあということで、1曲目お届けいたしましたのはReGLOSSでね、歌わせていただきました、Our Bright Paradeでした！皆さんどうでした？
Now, the first song we delivered was 'Our Bright Parade' by ReGLOSS! How was it, everyone?
どうだったかなみんな、おーおおって言ってくれてありがとうございます！チャットでね、応援してくれてる人もね、見えてますよ！ありがとうございます！
How was it? Thank you to everyone cheering with 'Ooh!' I can see those supporting in the chat as well! Thank you!
あ、舞茸をぐるぐるしてる人もね、いるっぽいです！ありがとうございます！舞茸ね、全然ぐるぐるしてくれて
Ah, looks like some people are spinning maitake mushrooms too! Thanks! Spinning those maitake around...
やっぱOur Bright Paradeね、最初の、やっぱReGLOSSの5人で歌いたいなっていうのとね、やっぱここからもうライブが始まっていくぞっていうね、こっからパレード始まっていくぞっていう曲なものでね、ちょっと1発目にね、歌わせていただきました！ありがとうございます！
With 'Our Bright Parade', I wanted us 5 in ReGLOSS to sing it first, and since it's a song about our live starting right here and our parade beginning from now on, I wanted to perform it first! Thank you!
えー今ReGLOSSの話がありましたが、今回のライブのテーマはここで出会ったのも何かのご縁でございます。えー本日の生誕ライブまでに1年と何ヶ月だ？活動してきて、もういろんな人との出会いがあって、で、いろんなことさせてもらって、ね、その中で今の自分があるので、ま、その感謝を伝えられるような今までのね、こう活動の奇跡になるような、そんなライブを目指しました。もうゲストの方たくさんね、いらっしゃいますので、お楽しみに、皆さんゲストパートへ！
Now, I was talking about ReGLOSS earlier, but the theme of this live is that meeting here is indeed a fateful encounter. Leading up to today's birthday live, having been active for a year and some months, I've met so many people and experienced so many things, which has led to who I am today. So I aimed for a live that could express my gratitude and reflect the miraculous journey of my activities so far. We have many guests joining us, so look forward to it everyone, moving on to the guest segment!
～収録でございます！
...is a recording!
……という事は、ソロパートはどうなるんだいって話でございます。
...which means, what's going to happen to the solo parts?
えー、なんとですね、なんとなんと！
Well, amazingly enough, unbelievably!
今回は、えー、リアルタイムでアンケート取ります。
This time, um, we'll be doing a real-time poll.
歌う楽曲にちなんだ、アンケートを取ろうと思っております。
We're going to take a poll related to the song we'll sing.
アンケートがね、ポコーンと出てきます。選択肢が二つあります。皆さんらはね、その二つの選択肢、うわどっちがいいかなあっていうのを悩んで、いっぱい悩んで、選んでください！
A poll will pop right up with two choices. Mull it over and choose whichever one you like best!
次の曲が終わるまでに選んでください。この次の曲ですね、この次の曲が終わるまでに選んでください。
Please make your choice before the next song ends. Before this upcoming song finishes.
そのアンケートの結果次第で、ソロパートで披露する曲が変わりますよ！
Depending on the poll results, the song I solo will change!
という事で、さっそく最初のアンケートはこちらでございます。ででーん！
So, without further ado, here is the first poll. Tada!
どちらの花を見に行く？ スミレの花 or ハスの花
[Which flowers to go see? Violet or Lotus]
今リアルタイムで見ていただいている方は、チャット欄にね、えー、出てきたと思います。
For those watching in real time, it should have popped up in the chat.
どちらの花を見に行きますか？ スミレの花、もしくはハスの花。さあ、皆さんお好きなほうをお選びください！
Which flower will you go see? Violets or lotuses? Everyone, please choose your favorite!
もしかしたら、じゃあこの花を選んだら実にあの日記曲なんじゃないかっていうね、予想も含めてね、楽しんでいただけると嬉しいです。
I hope you enjoy guessing whether picking a certain flower hints at a specific song!
では、さっそくですが、次の曲に行きたいと思います。ここでね、べらべら喋っててもアレなので、次の曲行きますよ。皆さん準備いいですか？
Well then, let's move on to the next song. Talking too much is awkward, so let's go. Are you ready?
あーっ！
Ah!
いきなりね、うん、ゲストのあの人が、え、登場するという事で、そんなこんなも何かのご縁登場します！
Suddenly, um, our guest is making an appearance, so by some chance they're appearing!
それでは行きましょう！どうぞ！
Then let's go! Here we go!
さよならはあなたから言った
You were the one who bid the farewell
それはなにを頬を濡らしてしまうのか
Even so, tears still run down your cheeks
そうやって昨日の事も消してしまうなら
If you're erasing all the past just like that
もういいよ 笑って
that's enough, just smile.
花束を抱えて歩いた 意味もなくただ街を見下ろした
I walked around with a bouquet of flowers in hand, just looking down at the town meaninglessly
こうやって理想の縁に心を置き去っていくのか もういいか 空っぽでいようぜ
And so I leave my feelings on the edge of my ideals, let's stay empty
それですべて深い青で満たしたのなら どうだろう こんな風に悩むのかな
And someday we would be filled with deep blue, how's that? Should we really be worried like this?
愛を 詠って 詠って 雲の上 濁りきっては 見えないや 嫌 嫌
I express and express my love, it's all beyond clouds, so thick I can't see it, no, no!
遠く 描いていた 日々を 語って 語って 夜の群れ
And the distant days we've been imagining, which we talk and talk about in the dusk of night
いがみ合って きりがないな 否 否
We bark at each other so much there's no end to it, none, none!
笑い合って さよなら
We laugh with each other as we bid our farewell
朝焼けとあなたの湊 この街は僕らの夢を見ている
Both the morning glow and your sigh, this town overlooks our dream
今日だって互いの事を忘れていくんだね ねえ そうでしょう
And even today we're trying to forget each other, right? Isn't that right?
黙っていようぜ それですべて 抉られたとしても別に良いんだよ
Let's stay silent, and someday even if torments will come upon us, I don't really mind
こんな 憂いも 意味があるなら 恋と 飾って 飾って 静かな方へ
Since this sorrow might even hold a meaning, I adorn and adorn with love, to the point of silence
汚れきった 言葉を 今 今 今
The filthy words, right now, now, now!
「此処には 誰もいない」 「ええ そうだね」
"There's no one here" "Yes, you're right"
混ざって 混ざって 二人の果て 譲り合った 何もないな 否 否
We mix and blend, and in the end of us, we give and take with each other, but there's nothing to it, none, none!
痛みだって 教えて きっと きっと わかっていた
At least tell me what pain is, surely, surely we knew that
騙し合うなんて 馬鹿らしいさ ずっと ずっと 迷っていた
We're fooling each other, how absurd, always, always lost we are
ほらね 僕らは 変われない そうだろう 互いのせいで 今があるのに
See, we always are, that's right, now we're here thanks to each other
愛を 詠って 詠って 雲の上 濁りきっては 見えないや 嫌 嫌
I express and express my love, it's all beyond clouds, so thick I can't see it, no, no!
日々に 増えていた 後悔を 語って 語って 夜の群れ
The regret that keeps piling up day by day, which we talk and talk about in the dusk of night
許し合って 意味もないな 否 否
Even if we forgive each other, there's no meaning to it, none, none!
愛を 詠って 詠って 雲の上
I express and express my love, it's all beyond clouds
語って 語って 夜の群れ
We talk and talk in the dusk of night
笑い合って さよなら
We laugh with each other as we bid our farewell
コンタース ハレイリア オン シャル イース
Resting our feet, on Charis...
アニム ゥ ミー タ ポリティマ イ ジュリーク
Holding our lantern high, we advance.
ズ ィ クロクロス オクノーク クレズ ディナツ ケイティーン
Yes, I have many guardian spirits.
ハプア ミュー キル シャ ル ベイル
This blessing will shake the bells of our homeland.
ヤィ ディ リラ レウ ミナス サクチュア
The princess protects the sanctuary from evil.
ディグ ナウ エ ミナス リガディア
The king becomes a sword that cuts down evil.
ディ シ ディ ラセイナ ヴェーティ カス
Even if swallowed by the vortex of another world,
ディ ミ ウォー イラ ジュ モロフ ハプア
Offering a blessing to her tomorrow.
ディ ミ ウォー イラ ジュ モロフ ホーラ
Offering a blessing to her tomorrow...
ディ ミ ウォー イラ ジュ モロフ フン
ハプア ミュー キル シャ ル ベイル
This blessing will shake the bells...
はーいということで、なんと今回、秋先輩に来ていただきました！
And so, Aki-senpai has come to join us today!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
みんなアロ～ハ！ホロライブ1期生のアキロゼことアキ・ローゼンタールです。はろはろはろアロ～ハ！
Hello everyone, Aloha! I'm Aki Rosenthal, 1st gen of Hololive. Hello hello hello Aloha!
やったー！ラデンちゃん、嬉しっちょよ～
Yay! Raden-chan, I'm so happy~
本日はお越しいただき誠にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming today!
いやいやいや、こちらこそ！すごく嬉しい！これ、歌させていただいた曲、シャルイース、アキ先輩のオリジナル曲を…
No, no, no, the pleasure is mine! I'm so happy! Getting to sing this song, Charis, Aki-senpai's original song...
一緒に歌わせていただき、こんなことがあっていいのかな！
Getting to sing it together, I can't believe this is happening!
めちゃめちゃ興奮してるんですよ。
I'm so super excited right now.
でもラデンちゃんがね、いつもうちのロゼのこのシャルイースを大好きだってこう、デビューのときから言ってくれてて、むしろロゼはねですっごい嬉しかったんで…
But Raden, you've always said how much you love my song "Charis" ever since your debut. I was actually so happy about that,
今日こうやって一緒に歌って、踊って、そのダンスレッスンもね、一緒にしたしですごいね楽しかった！むしろありがとうね！
so today getting to sing and dance together, taking dance lessons together too, it was so much fun! Thank you so much!
ええ、今回ライブタイトル、ね、ここで出会ったのも何かのご縁っていう感じでやらせてもらってるんですけど…
Well, this live title, you know, "meeting here is some kind of destiny," we're doing it with that feeling,
やっぱ、この曲がなければ、私もしもししてホロライブ知らなかった、世界線も…あって！
but if it weren't for this song, I might not have even known about Hololive, that timeline existed too!
ええ！？うそ！！知らなかった！
Eh?! No way!! I didn't know that!
すごくない！？嬉しい！
Isn't that amazing?! I'm so happy!
え、そうなの！？そうなんです！だから私にとってもすごく思い出のある曲で…
Is that so?! That's right! So it's a song with such precious memories for me...
もう、嬉しくて嬉しくて嬉しくて！良かった、ホロライブ入ってて！
I was so, so, so happy! I'm so glad I joined Hololive!
今思ったら、やばっ！
Thinking about it now, wow!
しかも、しかも、あの、私ジグロスがデビューして、最初のエキスポのとき、あき先輩シャルイース歌ってくださったんですよ。
And what's more, when ReGLOSS debuted and it was our first Expo, Aki-senpai sang "Charis."
そう、そう、そう！え、その話さ、ラデンちゃんが、好きって言ってくれたらしい…
That's right! And about that story, apparently Raden said she loved it...
そういう人生の節目もあったから、シャルイースを選んだ。
Because there were those milestones in life, I chose "Charis."
理由はのひとつにラデンちゃんが好きって言ってくれたから選んだんだよ。
One of the reasons I chose it was because Raden said she liked it.
えーー！！嬉しい！やったー！やったー！
Eeh!! I'm so happy! Yay! Yay!
こうやって3Dになって、同じ舞台に立てて…そうよ、そうよ！リハーサルだってめちゃめちゃうれしいです、タダです、ありがとうございます！
To be able to become 3D like this and stand on the same stage... That's right, that's right! Even the rehearsal was so super happy, it's free, thank you so much!
スパルタじゃなくてよかったですか？スパルタじゃないですか？大丈夫ですか？
Was it okay that it wasn't Spartan? Wasn't it Spartan? Are you okay?
いや、まあ、若干…嘘嘘嘘！いい匂い、いい匂い！
Well, I mean, slightly... Just kidding! You smell good, you smell good!
すごいにおわせるよ、大丈夫よ。
I'm really making it obvious, it's okay.
え、そのエキスポの時に、初めてお会いしたんですよね。そうだな、直接ね、あって。
Um, we met for the first time at that Expo, right? That's right, we met in person.
オンライン上ではたぶん何回かあって。そうだな、お話ししたりとかね、あったんですけど。
Online we probably met a few times. That's right, we talked and stuff.
その時に、なんて優しい人なんだと思って。
At that time, I thought what a kind person she was.
なんかリハーサル何かの時に、お隣に座らせていただいたんです。そしたらその時、なんて優しくて、太陽みたいな方なんだと…
During some rehearsal, you let me sit next to you. And at that time, I thought how kind and sun-like you were...
ええ、そんな褒めてくれるの？ちょっともう恋に落ちそうでした。ええー！そんなー！
Eh, you're praising me like that? I was about to fall in love. Eeh! No way!
え、でもラデンちゃんとは、なんかね、今年もっと仲良くなりたいなと思って…
But Raden, you know, I want us to get even closer this year...
思ってるから、ちょっといろいろさ、ついに、アキラデン解禁？
Because I think that, so let's do various things, finally, Aki-Raden unlocked?
やっと、やりたぐないしね！やりたぐないよ、みんな！
Finally, you don't want to do it! Everyone, I don't want to do it!
待ってた、待ってた、この時を。やったー！待ってた、待ってた、待ってた！
I've been waiting, waiting for this moment. Yay! Waiting, waiting, waiting!
じゃあ…
Now then...
今後も……仲良くしてくださいますか。
Will you continue to be good friends with me?
いや、今後はより一層、このご縁を膨らましていきましょう！
Let's nurture and expand this bond even more from now on!
はーい！やったー、よろしくお願いします！
Yay! Yay, I'm looking forward to it!
ありがとうございます、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much, thank you!
改めて本日は来ていただいて、本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you all so much for coming today!
またねー、ありがとねー！まったねー！
See you later, thank you! See you!
はい、というわけでございまして、そろそろね、皆さんに投票いただいているアンケート結果が出る頃だと思うっす！
Yes, and with that said, I think the survey results will be coming out soon!
えー、アンケート結果見て、で、ステージ移動しに行いたいと思います！アンケート結果見ていきましょう！こちられん、じゃじゃーん！
Let's check the survey results, and then move to the stage! Here we go, ta-da!
どちらの花を見に行く？ スミレの花
[Which flower to see? Violet]
なるほどね。そうだったのね。オッケー。じゃあ次の曲に行ってきます！でい！
I see. Is that so? Okay, then I'll head to the next song!
すみれ September Love
[Song: Sumire September Love]
それは九月だった
It was September,
あやしい季節だった
a mysterious time of year.
夕闇をドレスに変えて
Wearing your evening dress,
君が踊れば都も踊る
you danced and the city danced too.
まるでマンハッタン・ストーリー
Just like in a Manhattan story,
君さえいればパラダイス
if you are here, it's paradise.
昔見たシネマのように
Like an old movie we once saw,
恋に人生賭けてみようか
let's bet our lives on love.
You・You・You 誘惑の摩天楼
You, you, you, a skyscraper of temptation,
You・You・You 夢が花咲く
You, you, you, where dreams bloom.
すみれ September Love
Violet September Love,
踊ろう September dancing
let's dance, September dancing.
明日は明日ライラ・ライラ…
Tomorrow is tomorrow, la-la-la...
君は夢幻
You are a dream's illusion.
すみれ September Love again
Violet September Love again,
今夜は September dreaming
tonight, we're September dreaming.
ゆらゆらゆら揺られてライライ・ライライ
Swaying side to side, lai-lai, lai-lai.
君は奇跡だった
You were a miracle,
優しい天使だった
a gentle angel.
あきらめを覚えかけてた
My heart, which had almost given up,
僕の心にふれた微笑み
felt your gentle smile.
You・You・You 許されるものならば
You, you, you, if it's allowed,
You・You・You 夢の続きを
You, you, you, the continuation of the dream...
すみれ September Love
Violet September Love,
踊ろう September dancing
let's dance, September dancing.
明日は明日ライラ・ライラ…
Tomorrow is tomorrow, la-la-la...
君は君の幻
You are your own illusion.
すみれ September Love again
Violet September Love again,
今夜は September dreaming
tonight, we're September dreaming.
ゆらゆらゆら揺られてライライ・ライライ
Swaying side to side, lai-lai, lai-lai.
ということで、ということで、
And so, and so,
えー、選ばれたのは、すみれセプテンバーラブ...
Um, the one chosen was Sumire September Love...
選ばれたのは、すみれセプテンバーラブでございました！
The one chosen was Sumire September Love!
ありがとうございましたー！えー、すみれの花は、あ、ハスの...
Thank you very much! Um, the flower of Sumire is—ah, Lotus—
選ばれたのはすみれの花でしたのでね、お、チャット欄で予想していた方がいた通り、
the one chosen was Sumire's flower, so as some people predicted in the chat,
え、すみれセプテンバーラブ、え、ただ今回は一風堂さんバージョンではなく、
Sumire September Love... but this time, not the Ippu-Do version,
シャズナさんバージョンのすみれセプテンバーラブ披露させていただきました！
but SHAZNA's version of Sumire September Love was performed!
ありがとうございましたー！で、ちょ、アンケート結果がね、
Thank you very much! Now, about the poll results,
ごめん、ちょっとそんなに体力なくてね、ええと、えー、58対41くらいだったそうござい... 結構接戦！
sorry, I don't have that much stamina... Um, it was around 58 to 41... Quite a close match!
ですね！あ、結構ね、差がついた、んじゃないかなと思っておりますが、
Right? Um, I think a bit of a gap formed, though,
なんと！なんとここでですね、なんとハッシュタグ、ラでん生誕祭2025、トレンド、1位らしくて！やったーみんなー！
and what do you know! Right here, the hashtag #RadenBirthday2025 is apparently #1 on trending! Yay, everyone!
トレンド1位でございます！やったうれしー！
It's #1 on trending! Yay, I'm so happy!
え、この後もね、まだまだ生誕ライブ続きますので、いっぱい感想を呟いていただけるとうれしいです。
Um, the birthday live continues after this, so I'd be happy if you keep tweeting your thoughts.
ということで、え、ここで出会ったのも何かのご縁、第2回目のアンケートでございます！まだありますよー、アンケートでございます！
And so, meeting here is also fate—it's time for our second poll! There's still more, it's a poll!
じゃあさっそくね、見ていきましょう、次のアンケートはこちらです！じゃじゃーん！
Let's check right away, the next poll is right here! Ta-da!
はい、え、アンケートどちらに行こうか、え、寄席 or 美術館、寄席 or 美術館です。
Yes, the poll: 'Where should we go?' Yosese or Art Museum, Yosese or Art Museum.
まあ、ちょっとね、あの、何かしらのヒントくれよって言う方がいらっしゃるかもしれないからなんですけど、
Well, some of you might be asking for some kind of hint,
え、新、新しいラでんを見たかったら寄席、可愛いラでんを見たかったら美術館って感じでございます。
so if you want to see a new Raden, choose Yosese; if you want to see a cute Raden, choose Art Museum.
さあ、ぜひ皆さんどしどしご回答ください。
Now everyone, please be sure to vote!
え、次の曲ね、この次の曲が終わるまでに選んでください。次の曲が終わったら締め切っちゃいますよ。
Please choose by the time the next song ends. Voting closes as soon as the next song finishes.
さあ、ということでね、えー、そんなアンケートも皆さんに答えてもらいつつなんですが、
And so, while you all answer that poll,
次の曲は、あのゲストお二人が登場します！その次の曲も、あのゲストが... あ、あ、えー！？
for the next song, two guest performers will appear! And for the song after that, that guest... wait, what?!
それではゲストパートです！どうぞー！
And now, it's the guest part! Here we go!
Go to 鎌倉 DANCE 明かすよSUN
Go to Kamakura DANCE, revealing the sun,
巡る時代 踊り踊りな Wow Wow
Dancing through the revolving eras, Wow Wow
ステップ タップ リズムに乗って
Riding the step-tap rhythm,
鎌倉 STYLE! よよよ来福 明日からは平安からの鎌倉
Kamakura STYLE! Bringing good fortune from tomorrow, Kamakura from the Heian era
南北朝から令和まで 鎌倉 STYLE! 鎌倉 STYLE!
From the Nanbokucho to Reiwa, Kamakura STYLE! Kamakura STYLE!
1185 いはこー！ 1192 いくに！ 合戦もゆーのー 超ゆーの！
1185, let's build! 1192, building the nation! Battles are also Yuno, super Yuno!
思い詰まった時代は鎌倉 進め南北朝まで荒らすわ
An era of deep worries is Kamakura, advancing to sweep through the Nanbokucho period
一所懸命 自分とレペゼン 犬を追い物試合に平癒
With all my heart, representing myself, dog-chasing matches and healing
琵琶法師に水鏡 気抜くすて！ 鎌倉STYLE!
Biwa hoshi and water mirror, don't let your guard down! Kamakura STYLE!
若衆随一 立志なんでき 神社にぶっかくあやかって
The foremost youths determined to succeed, taking inspiration from the shrines
どんな時代も僕たちは楽しさから逃れられない
In any era, we can never escape from fun
Go to 鎌倉 DANCE 明かすよSUN Wow Wow
Go to Kamakura DANCE, revealing the sun, Wow Wow
巡る時代 踊り踊りな Wow Wow
Dancing through the revolving eras, Wow Wow
連れ去るままに Go the way 和楽器鳴らして Fly away
Carried away, Go the way, playing Japanese instruments, Fly away
超未来まで繋いでく
Connecting to the distant future
Go to 鎌倉 DANCE かます乱れ髪
Go to Kamakura DANCE, showing off disheveled hair
鼻唄が聞こえたら
When humming is heard,
ステップ タップ リズムに乗って
Riding the step-tap rhythm,
ステップアップ 大人になって
Stepping up, becoming an adult,
鎌倉STYLE! 鎌倉STYLE!
Kamakura STYLE! Kamakura STYLE!
ドンドン ドンドン ドンドン ガンガン 踊れ踊れ！
Don-don don-don don-don gan-gan, dance, dance!
琵琶法師に大工物語 どこまで行ってもあの娘目くのし
Biwa hoshi and carpenter tales, no matter how far, that girl's eyes...
ビーヒャラ ビーヒャラ シャンシャンシャン 僕と一緒に踊りませんか？
Bee-hyara bee-hyara shan-shan-shan, won't you dance with me?
なんて言えないこんばんは！ 鎌倉SHOCK!
Can't say that, good evening! Kamakura SHOCK!
争いごとは絶えないし 悲しいニュースも尽きないし
Conflicts never end, and sad news never stops either
こんな世界で僕たちは
In this world, the two of us
幸せのこと探していくんだ
are searching for happiness.
誰も知らない
No one knows...
ありのままで 生きてゆける
I can live on just as I am.
誰も知らない 踊る時間
An unknown time to dance,
いつまでも 笑うのよ
smiling forever.
裂けた心を踊れ
Dance with a torn heart.
行くよ！
Let's go!
鎌倉DANCE 笑えばSUN SUN
Kamakura DANCE, sunny smiles!
巡る時代 前々LOVE ON
Revolving eras, forever LOVE ON!
縦横無尽ままに Go the way
Freely going our own way,
和楽器鳴らして Fly away
playing traditional instruments, fly away!
超未来まで繋いでく
Connecting to the ultra-future.
鎌倉DANCE 笑えばSUN SUN
Kamakura DANCE, sunny smiles!
恋の予感 進めよヤング
Premonition of love, push forward, young ones!
レッツダッシュ 思いのまま
Let's dash, just as you wish!
さあ行こう鎌倉 からの平安からの鎌倉
Kamakura, then Heian, then Kamakura!
南北朝から室町へ 安土桃山江戸時代
From Nanbokucho to Muromachi, Azuchi-Momoyama, Edo!
明治大正昭和まで 平成からの令和
Meiji, Taisho, Showa, Heisei to Reiwa!
次はどんな未来が待ってる 俺たちが創り上げていく
Whatever future awaits, we will build it!
ステップ タップ リズムに乗って
Step, tap, riding the rhythm,
手を振って 大人になって
waving our hands and growing up.
鎌倉STYLE
Kamakura STYLE!
太陽は綺麗！
The sunset is so beautiful!
大丈夫ですか？息ととのえて... 大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay? Catch your breath... Are you okay?
今日のゲストさん、竜ヶ崎リンさんのお二人に来ていただきました！ありがとうございます！
Today's guests are Ryugasaki Rin and Kousaka! Thank you both!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
はい、メイドバーチャル音楽ユニット「Mostonement」のボーカル担当でキュウ血鬼、高坂と...
I'm Kousaka, vampire vocalist of the maid unit Mostonement...
ほい、774inc. 所属、竜ヶ崎リンと申します。誕生日おめでとうございます！
And I'm Ryugasaki Rin from 774inc. Happy birthday!
おめでとうございます！ありがとうございます！そしてお呼ばれいただきありがとうございます！
Happy birthday! Thank you so much! And thanks for having us!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ええ、これね、なぜこのお二人をお呼びしたかと申しますと...
Now, why did I invite these two today, you ask?
ええ、去年2024年の3月10日のラジオで、V-Rurとラジオがあったんですが、そこで共演させていただいて
Last March 10, 2024, on a radio show called V-Rur, we co-starred,
で、あの、カットされたところではあるんですけど、いつか一緒にお歌いたいです！って、そこで言ったので、
and though that part was cut, I said I wanted to sing together someday!
私が私のわがままでお今日叶えに来てくださいました！
So at my selfish request, you came to make it happen today!
本当にありがとうございます！ いやいや、そんな... ありがたいねえ。
Thank you so much! No, no... We're so grateful.
切実な... 我々と一緒にお歌いたいだなんてありがたいよね。
Such a heartfelt... It's so touching that you wanted to sing with us.
本当俺らみたいなお笑いみたいなやつらと... もう音楽の大先輩ですから！いやいや、ありがとうございます！とっても一緒にお歌えて楽しくて嬉しいです！ありがとうございます！
Really, with clowns like us... But you're musical seniors! Thank you so much! It was so much fun!
いやこの「鎌倉STYLE」って曲もね、すごくノリの良い曲で、一人で歌うのもいいけどちょっと... だから誰かと一緒に歌いたいな！みたいな...
"Kamakura STYLE" has such a great groove; singing it alone is nice, but I wanted to sing with someone!
ところがあって、ちょっとドキドキしながらお声がけさせていただいたですけれども、快く来ていただきました！本当にありがとうございます！
So with a bit of heart-pounding nervousness, I reached out, and you readily came! Thank you!
楽しかった！
It was so fun!
とりあえずリハでね、間奏の部分でぐるぐる回るのをやってたんですけど...
During rehearsal, we practiced spinning around in the instrumental break,
ま、ラデンさんが死んでしまうということで、ちょっと本番はやめようと。
but since Raden was going to die from it, we decided to skip it for the live.
そうですね、息が上がって上がってね、ラデンのずっと楽しそうだから。
My breathing just kept getting higher and higher, because Raden always looks like she's having so much fun.
ずっと楽しそうなんだよね。
She always looks so happy.
楽しかったし、なんか、あのリハの最中に高坂さんが私に「あれ、そんなキャラだっけ？」
It was fun, and during rehearsal Kousaka-san asked me, "Wait, is that your character?"
「あれ、ラデジってそんなキャラだっけ？」初めて会った時さ...
"Wait, is Radeji that kind of character?" When we first met...
ほら、「あ、なんて聡明な刀なんだろうか」って言われたのめっちゃ覚えてるの！
I remember you saying, "Ah, what a wise sword it is!"
そしたら今日めちゃくちゃエンジンかかってるわ！私より、僕よりマジ元気！
And today your engine is running at full throttle! You've got way more energy than me!
びっくりしちゃって。
I was so surprised.
ま、でもおかげさまでリハーサルからずっと楽しくてね、ずっと楽しくてね、ありがとうございました！
Well, thanks to you, rehearsals were always so fun, thank you!
ステージの上でも楽しかった！めちゃくちゃ！めちゃくちゃ楽しかった！
And it was so fun on stage too! Absolutely!
いや、嬉しい、ありがとう！いや、嬉しい！ありがとうございます！
It was so fun. I'm so glad, thank you!
なんか宣伝していきますか？雑把に...
Would you like to do some promotions?
まあ、我々もね活動してるんですけど、まあ、なんかXなりYouTubeチャンネルなり見ていただければ。
Well, if you could check out our X or YouTube channels...
今日はもうラデンさんおめでとございますと、ライブもまだまだ続くので...
Today is Raden-san's birthday, and the live stream is still ongoing,
まあ、僕らから言うこともありませんが、最後までぜひ皆さんも盛り上がっていって、いただければと思います。
so we hope everyone will keep the excitement going until the very end.
改めて、ラデンさんお誕生日おめでとうございます！
Once again, happy birthday, Raden-san!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
ライブもまだまだ続くので... 引き続き楽しんでください！頑張ります！バイバーイ！
Please keep enjoying the show! We'll do our best! Bye-bye!
お二人ともありがとうございました！
Thank you both so much!
次の曲もなんとゲストが... ゲストの... 方がいらっしゃいます！それではどうぞ！
The next song features some wonderful guests! Here they are!
プリーズ... ジェントルマン... 息はよいよい帰りは笑い...
Please, ladies and gentlemen...
Finds and enjoys in the paradise
oh what a dis, oh what a dis
気づけば気になって でも君も同じ
Before I knew it, I was curious, but you're the same too.
もう十分よってるだけのお遊び
That's enough, just a chasing game.
我慢できない誘惑と好奇心
Can't resist this temptation and curiosity.
woo 瞳の向こう
Woo, beyond our eyes,
woo 隠してるもの
woo, something hidden,
woo, yeah, it's so bad, it's good
気持ち覗かないと
I need to peek into your heart.
narcissistic, my god i love it
互い照らす審判
The judgment that illuminates each other,
美しい眼差しく深く落ち
diving deep into those beautiful eyes.
(そう君と私と)
(You and me)
息止め love dive
Hold your breath, love dive.
woo la-la-la-la-la-la-la
woo いっそもっと love dive
woo, come on in, love dive,
woo, oh, perfect sacrifice, yeah
息止め love dive
Hold your breath, love dive.
分かったようで分からない気持ち
Feelings that seem understood yet unknown,
だって一瞬で咲くものこそ愛
because love blooms in an instant.
来ればいいじゃない
You can come
心の深淵へ
into the deepest part of my heart.
woo 迷う時間
Woo, time to hesitate,
woo 3秒で十分
woo, 3 seconds is enough,
woo, yeah, it's so bad, it's good
望むなら飛び込め
If you want, dare to dive in.
narcissistic, my god i love it
互い照らす審判
The judgment that illuminates each other,
美しい眼差し深く落ち
diving deep into those beautiful eyes.
(そう君と私と)
(You and me)
息止め love dive
Hold your breath, love dive.
woo la-la-la-la-la-la-la
woo いっそもっと love dive
woo, come on in, love dive,
woo, oh, perfect sacrifice, yeah
息止め love dive
Hold your breath, love dive.
Hold your breath, love dive,
息止め love dive
hold your breath, love dive,
hold your breath, love dive.
woo la-la-la-la-la-la-la
woo いっそもっと love dive
woo, come on in, love dive,
woo, oh, perfect sacrifice, yeah
息止め love dive
Hold your breath, love dive.
踊ろととろは 恨めしやもめ
Dance and drift, a resentful widow,
華ぐぞわレレレイ
flowers bloom, rererei.
歌舞伎は華麗バレレレイ
Kabuki is gorgeous, barereray.
ダブルダブル 生まれ浮かんだ 言葉で憎まれは ほまれだとさとる メガネの裏
Double double, born and floating words, being hated is seen as honor behind the glasses.
事件な顔して さらさらいたら 眠るしかばね
With a serious face, if you leave it be, you're a sleeping corpse.
また盛り上げていきましょう
Let's hype it up again!
絡み付かせ変狂
Entangling obsession,
バレぬようにやで 調戦言
declaring a challenge so you won't be caught.
弾き込んだ手札 暴かれるは
The hand you drew will be exposed,
握る背をえほえも
grasping your back, ehoemo.
ready, set, gentlemen
please enjoy in the paradise oh what a dis, oh what a dis
笑いの日だとか われちはダブル
Days of laughter or we are double,
がった歌舞伎だから こぼれるわらわらわら
because it's a double Kabuki, spilling laughter.
ダブルダブル わったら せわだぶ だぶだぶ
Double double, if it cracks, it's busy, double double.
からまったせわだぶ だぶだぶ
Tangled and busy, double double.
からまったせわは リアるねのたぼ
Tangled business is real's taboo.
キャラはキャラだ あばかすざるらに なんどだって
Characters are characters, no matter how many times,
生まれ変わるなら やっぱりせわだぶ だぶだぶ
if I'm reborn, it's still double double.
からまったせわが 胸の上越えど
Tangled business crossing over the chest,
笑い飛ばせ 遊ばせ あばがらのサイボー
laugh it off, let them play, with wild cyborgs.
ややわらわのわ わらけり遊ばせ さらば終わるりんねや
Laughing and playing, farewell to the ending cycle.
わらわのわあ
My laughter...
レスト！
Rest!
あらか あらか あらか あらか はい
Araka araka araka araka, hai!
笑いの日だとか われちはダブル
Days of laughter or we are double,
がった歌舞伎だから こぼれるわらわらわら
because it's a double Kabuki, spilling laughter.
ダブルダブル！
Double double!
お邪魔してます！おめでとう！ありがとう！
We're intruding! Congratulations! Thank you!
おめでとうだよ！ありがとう！
Congratulations! Thank you!
息止めてもらって、ふふっ。というわけで…
Hold your breath, haha. So...
なんだとゲスト、3組目は姫ヒナのお二人にお越しいただきました！お邪魔しております！
And our guests for the 3rd group are HimeHina! We're intruding!
じゃあ、挨拶しますか。せーの、はーい！
Shall we do our greetings? Ready, set, hi!
田中ヒメです！
I'm Hime Tanaka!
鈴木ヒナです！二人合わせて…
I'm Hina Suzuki! Together we're...
姫ヒナです！よろしくお願いします！
HimeHina! Nice to meet you!
おめでとう！おめでとうおめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
本物！？あはははは！
The real deal!? Hahaha!
あれ、ご本人、ご本人じゃ……あははは！
Wait, it's the real person, aren't they... hahaha!
落ち行く花びらを表現してました。あ、なるほど、ここがめでたいしね。
Expressing falling petals. Ah, I see, that's why it's celebratory.
おめでと、おめでと！うん、本当にめでたいのかこれ？分かんない！あははは！
Congratulations, congratulations! Yeah, is this really celebratory? I have no idea! Hahaha!
はい、ということでございまして、え、ダブルダブルを、え、ダブルダブル、一緒にね、歌わせていただきました。ありがとうございます！
Yes, with that said, we got to sing "Double Double" together. Thank you so much!
ずっとこの曲が大好きで。嬉しい！嬉しい！ねえ、一緒にできてよかったよ。
I've always loved this song so much. I'm so happy! So happy! I'm glad we could do it together.
嬉しくて。でね、あの伏線もちゃんとあったんですよね。一度コラボに、そうだな。
I'm so happy. And you know, there was foreshadowing for this too. Once before for a collaboration, that's right.
お呼びいただきまして、そうなん、コラボかな？コラボだね。12月？12月？
You invited us, that's right, was it a collaboration? It was a collaboration. December? December?
一月まっすぐぐらい？
Around straight into January?
ぐらいだね。
Right around there.
ぐらいね。
Right.
そこね、ダブダブが好きだからって言ってたんです
She said she likes dub-dub there...
が、その伏線が今日回収されました！やったー！
But that foreshadowing was resolved today! Yay!
嬉しいー！どうなったかなー？
I'm so happy! How did it turn out?
いやー、すごいさ、振り付けもすごいしっかり覚えてくれてさ、
Man, she learned the choreography so well,
歌もめっちゃかっこいい！ありがとうございます！
and the song is super cool! Thank you very much!
ちょっとね、ダンスはね、ちょこちょこ、ちょこちょこミスってるので
As for the dance, she made a few minor mistakes here and there,
ぜひアーカイブでご確認ください
please check the archive.
間違い探しだ！ちょっとやり直すんで
It's spot the difference! Since we're redoing it...
始まる前もさ、はじっこで一生懸命練習しててね
Even before it started, she was working hard practicing in the corner.
我々もこうやって、盛り上がってね
And we were getting hyped up like this.
本当に贅沢すぎるダンスの先生がね、ありがとうございました！
Such a luxury dance teacher, thank you very much!
3人の踊りの最高潮を見たかった！見たかった！見たかった！
We wanted to see the climax of the three dancing!
なんか、こう言うのちょっと久しぶりになるのかな？
It's been a while since we did something like this, hasn't it?
ま、ちょっとね、久しぶり、久しぶりだけどね
Well, yeah, it's been a bit, a little while.
いや、でも我々と言えばもうさ、ミリオン同期だよ！
But speaking of us, we're million-view syncmates!
ミリオン同期！100万人おめでとう！
Million syncmates! Congratulations on 1 million!
おめでとう！おめでとう！おめでとう！ちょっと待って、1、1、1、1作って
Congratulations! Congratulations! Congratulations! Wait, make 1, 1, 1, 1...
8だね、180万、180万だ、それ。はい、180万人！おめでとうございます！
It's 8, 1.8 million, 1.8 million. Yes, 1.8 million! Congratulations!
おめでて、同じくらいの時期にね、100万人を達成しまして、ミリオン同期ということで
Congratulations, we reached 1 million around the same time, so we're million syncmates.
素晴らしいですね。今後もね、仲良くしていただきたいんですけども、
That's wonderful. We hope to get along well in the future too.
よろしくお願いいたします。
Please treat us well.
いや、でもまださ、なんか、あれ？あれあれ？なんか、なんかある気がするけど
Wait, but still, like, huh? It feels like there's something else...
もっとさ、やりたいし、ねえ？二足で入りました！
We want to do more, right? We stepped in on both feet!
まだまだお楽しみがあったらいーい、ないのかなってね
Wondering if there are still more treats in store...
あるのかな？もっともっと色々やってこ！そうやっていこ、うん。やっていきましょう！はい。
Is there? Let's do all sorts of more things! Let's do it!
ツアーもお疲れ様でした！ありがとう！
Good work on the tour too! Thank you!
そう、来てくれてもう超うれしかった！ありがとう！
Yeah, I was so super happy you came! Thank you!
もう1曲目バーって始まった瞬間からボロ泣き。そう、すごい好きって言ってくれるから
From the moment the first song started, I was in tears, because she said she loves it so much.
もうこっちも気合い入るよ本当に。もう大好きだからもうツアーの最初でも泣き、100万人達成でも泣き
It really gets us pumped. I cried at the start, I cried at 1 million.
いや、立派なジョージでございます。本当によく頑張った！ありがとう！
Man, what a fine gorgeous she is. You worked so hard! Thank you!
ハイファイもね、100万で歌ってくれてさ、絶対歌おうと思ってたんだ。ありがとう！
You sang High-Five at 1 million too, I was determined to sing it. Thank you!
なんて素敵なタイミングでね！お祝いできて嬉しいね！
What a wonderful timing! So happy we could celebrate!
なんかね、あの、100万人達成緊急配信をされてたじゃない？
You know, wasn't there an emergency stream for reaching 1 million?
あの、ちょっとタグとかで「きみら100万人で」ってつけて投稿したら
Like, if you post with tags like "you guys at 1 million",
配信中に「なんかラデンちゃんがつぶやいてくれてる」って
during the stream "looks like Raden-chan posted something"...
認知されてる恥ずかしい。コラボしてるのに認知もないわけないよ！
Being recognized is embarrassing. Of course you're recognized!
そうか！そうそうそうですやん。ファンの人みんなに教えてくれてね
Ah, that's right! You taught all the fans.
改めておめでとうございます！そしておめでとうございます！おめでとうリンさん！
Congratulations once again! Congratulations Rin-san!
よろしくお願いします！お願いします！
Please treat us well! Please do!
はい、ということでございまして、えー、ひみちゃんさのお二人に来ていただきました。本日は本当にありがとうございました！
Yes, thank you two for coming today. Thank you so much!
ありがとう！ありがとう！おめでとうだよ！おめでとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you! Congratulations!
じゃあ、いきますか。はい、締めましょうか。ありがとみんな、バイバーイ！
Well, shall we go? Let's wrap up. Thanks everyone, bye-bye!
え、え、え、別々？え？おおー！バイバーイ！
Eh, separate? Ohh! Bye-bye!
はい、ということでございましてね、ちょっとだいぶただのファンになっちゃったんですけど後半。お二人とも本当にありがとうございました！
I kinda turned into just a fan in the second half. Thank you both!
さて、皆さんそろそろですね、アンケートの結果が出たところだと思うんですけど、ドキドキのアンケート結果見ていこうと思います。アンケート結果はこちらでん！
Now everyone, let's take a look at the exciting questionnaire results!
さあ、皆さん、ラデン生誕祭2025楽しんでますかー！みんなー！
Now everyone, are you enjoying Raden's Birthday Festival 2025?!
さあ、今から披露する曲は、皆さんのアンケートでね、え、美術たんが多かったので美術にまつわる曲歌っちゃいますよ。
The next song is based on your art requests, so let's enjoy it!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ピー ピピ ピピ ピカソ も ダビンチ も
P-Pi-Pi-Pi-Picasso and Da Vinci,
好きな もの だけ 自分 で 決める
decide what you like all on your own.
Oh oh get away from escaping is…
Oh, oh, get away, from escaping is...
指先隠した 自覚するは
Awakening the self hidden at my fingertips,
弱さと逃げ出したい心は亡霊だ
weakness and the desire to run away are phantoms.
クラクラ暗い性もない
Pitch black, not even gloomy,
明日さえ図れない
can't even picture tomorrow,
無い物ねだりと笑う虚像は?
smiling at nothing, what is this illusory image?
曖昧じゃん言い淀んでさ
Ambiguous, mumbling nonsensically,
やってらんないぜ 独裁決定
no way we're doing that, autocratic decision.
大体は裏腹さ 不器用絶賛証明
Mostly two-faced, clumsiness is stellar proof.
知りもしないことも 上で育む
Things I don't even know are growing above,
ワンルーム 響く は知らない?
echoing in one room—is that something I don't know?
歌を聴いて 毒で濡れた 歌は未だ
Listen to the song, stained with poison, the song is still unformed.
知らない 嫌いを 試したいだけ?
Just wanting to try an unfamiliar disgust?
不正視界負世界愛じゃない
Distorted field of vision, negative world, not love.
弱い自分じゃいられないから 飾りたい 徒写する
Since I can't accept my weak self, I want to decorate and project it.
La ta ta 感情じゃ 曖昧じゃ
La ta ta, not emotion, not ambiguity,
知ってたんじゃんか 連続性
did you know? Continuity,
だから変わらない それは変われない
so it doesn't change, that won't change either,
だけど代わりなんさ 腐っちまうほど?
but a substitute? To the point of rotting away?
あれも欲しい だけど 不耐性? 歓声だ 完全だ?
Wanting that too, but impatience? Acclamation? Perfection?
満たせない心 両価性
An unfulfilling heart, ambivalence.
祭壇 咲いた 憂いはバラバラ
The shrine bloomed, sorrows are scattered everywhere.
両方制裁 逃避気持ちいいいおん
Bilateral control, evasion, how does it feel?
酔狂知った 生を躙った 愛を知ったんじゃないかって?
Intoxicated, knowing life, wasn't this knowing love?
最愛でした は自分自身だった
It was my absolute favorite—it was myself.
変わりたいだけだけど知ってる だから私じゃないと説得
I just want to change, but I know, so I persuade myself it's not me.
もういいよ いいよ 言い出したんだ 伽藍堂だ 心臓
Enough already, I let it slip, it's the Garan-do, my heartbeat.
知らない言葉で穿さないで 秘めたい事柄探さないで
Don't read me with unfamiliar words, don't probe into my hidden secrets.
再現性すらない災難だ 狂っていていいかな ha-
A disaster without even reproducibility, go ahead and go mad, hah—
壊れるくらいならいいさ 吹かせ 砕け 綺麗なままで?
If it's to the point of breaking, fine, let it blow, shatter, and stay beautiful?
私を映して で知った君を 歌い出したんだ
Reflecting me, I came to know you and started to sing.
患い 揺らぎだ まだ見たいから
Ailment, shaking, because I still want to see it,
孤独ではないと気付けないから 聴かせ続けた自分自身
since I can't realize I'm not alone, I kept listening to myself.
羅針盤の共鳴
The resonance of the compass.
つまらない 殺したい 掠りたい 奪いたい まだ まだ 知ら ない 鏡心 uh la la
Boring, want to kill, want to plunder, want to steal, still, still don't know, mirror heart, uh la la.
ただ ただ 殺し 足らない 嘆声 や だ 逆さま 空虚 だ la ta ta
Just, just kill, not enough, lamentation, oh, it's upside down, emptiness, la ta ta.
はい、 ここで 楽曲の途中ですが
Alright, that's it for the song.
宣伝があります！
We have an announcement!
じゃーん なんと現在 箱根ガラスの森美術館にて
Right now, at the Hakone Glass-no-Mori Museum,
お子さま用音声ガイドを担当中 私九十九とらでんと 本ライブの先輩の 白い恋人先輩の二人で担当させていただいております
we are providing the audio guides for children! It's hosted by Shirayuki Reid and me, Raden.
お子さま用音声ガイドとは 言っても大人の人が聞いてもめちゃめちゃ面白い音声ガイドとなっております
Even though it's called a children's audio guide,
期間は7月13日までとなっております
it has become super interesting even for adults to listen to.
ぜひとも皆さん 箱根に足を運んでください！
The period is until July 13th, so everyone, please visit Hakone!
何卒何卒 何卒何卒 何卒よろしくお願いいします！
Thank you very much! Thank you very much! Thank you very much! Thank you very much!
Oh oh get away from escaping is…
Oh, oh, get away, from escaping is...
指先隠した 自覚するは
Awakening the self hidden at my fingertips,
弱さと逃げ出したい心は亡霊だ
weakness and the desire to run away are phantoms.
クラクラ暗い性もない
Pitch black, not even gloomy,
明日さえ図れない
can't even picture tomorrow,
無い物ねだりと笑う虚像は?
smiling at nothing, what is this illusory image?
曖昧じゃん言い淀んでさ
Ambiguous, mumbling nonsensically,
やってらんないぜ 独裁決定
no way we're doing that, autocratic decision.
大体は裏腹さ 不器用絶賛証明
Mostly two-faced, clumsiness is stellar proof.
知りもしないことも 上で育む
Things I don't even know are growing above,
ワンルーム 響く は知らない?
echoing in one room—is that something I don't know?
歌を聴いて 毒で濡れた 歌は未だ
Listen to the song, stained with poison, the song is still unformed.
知らない 嫌いを 試したいだけ?
Just wanting to try an unfamiliar disgust?
不正視界負世界愛じゃない
Distorted field of vision, negative world, not love.
弱い自分じゃいられないから 飾りたい 徒写する
Since I can't accept my weak self, I want to decorate and project it.
La ta ta 感情じゃ 曖昧じゃ
La ta ta, not emotion, not ambiguity,
知ってたんじゃんか 連続性
did you know? Continuity,
だから変わらない それは変われない
so it doesn't change, that won't change either,
だけど代わりなんさ 腐っちまうほど?
but a substitute? To the point of rotting away?
あれも欲しい だけど 不耐性? 歓声だ 完全だ?
Wanting that too, but impatience? Acclamation? Perfection?
満たせない心 両価性
An unfulfilling heart, ambivalence.
祭壇 咲いた 憂いはバラバラ
The shrine bloomed, sorrows are scattered everywhere.
両方制裁 逃避狂おしいい
Bilateral control, evasion, madly obsessed.
酔狂知った 生を躙った 愛を知った体でいいで
Intoxicated, knowing life, is it fine to have a body that knows love?
最愛でした は自分自身でいい
It was my absolute favorite—it was myself.
変わりたいだけだけど知ってる だから私じゃないと説得
I just want to change, but I know, so I persuade myself it's not me.
もういいよ いいよ 言い出したんだ 伽藍堂だ 心臓
Enough already, I let it slip, it's the Garan-do, my heartbeat.
知らない言葉で穿さないで 秘めたい事柄探さないで
Don't read me with unfamiliar words, don't probe into my hidden secrets.
再現性すらない災難だ 狂っていていいかな ha-
A disaster without even reproducibility, go ahead and go mad, hah—
壊れるくらいならいいさ 吹かせ 砕け 綺麗なままで?
If it's to the point of breaking, fine, let it blow, shatter, and stay beautiful?
私を映して で知った君を 歌い出したんだ
Reflecting me, I came to know you and started to sing.
患い 揺らぎだ まだ見たいから
Ailment, shaking, because I still want to see it,
孤独ではないと気付けないから 聴かせ続けた自分自身
since I can't realize I'm not alone, I kept listening to myself.
羅針盤の共鳴
The resonance of the compass.
つまらない 殺したい 掠りたい 奪いたい まだ まだ 知ら ない 鏡心 uh la la
Boring, want to kill, want to plunder, want to steal, still, still don't know, mirror heart, uh la la.
ただ ただ 殺し 足らない 嘆声 や だ 逆さま 空虚 だ la ta ta
Just, just kill, not enough, lamentation, oh, it's upside down, emptiness, la ta ta.
祭壇 咲いた 憂いはバラバラ
The shrine bloomed, sorrows are scattered everywhere.
両方制裁 逃避狂おしいい
Bilateral control, evasion, wildly obsessed.
はぁーい
Phew...
というわけで皆さん
So, everyone,
アンケートのご協力ありがとうございました！
thank you very much for your cooperation in the survey!
選ばれた曲は えー
The chosen song was...
52%美術館でピピカソでございました！
52% Museum - "Pipikaso"!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
4万7000票くらい入ってた！
It had about 47,000 votes in it.
そうです、ありがとうございます！
Is that right? Thank you very much!
でね、曲の冒頭で あの、あれしたんですけど、なんとハッシュタグらでん生誕祭2025 日本とそれからトレンドの 1位なんでございまーす！って皆さん
And actually, right at the beginning of the song, I did that, but it ranked #1 in Japan and worldwide for #HashtagRadenBirthday2025!
しんどかないな！
Unbelievable!
まあこんな信じられなさもらでんぽいっちゃらでんぽいのでね。
Well, this unbelievable part is very Raden-like, isn't it?
えーで、ちなみに 今回のね アンケートで 選ばれなかった曲はどうするんじゃいっていうお話でございますが
And by the way, what happens to the songs that weren't chosen in this survey?
なんと選ばれなかった曲に関しては、このあとメンバー限定のアンコールライブで選ばれなかった方の曲を、まあアナザー なんとかかんとかみたいな感じで、えーやろうと思います。
As for the songs that weren't chosen, after this, we'll do them in a member-limited encore live as "another... something like that," and do them!
なのでね、ちょっと気になるー！気になるなー！
So I'm a bit curious, I'm curious.
ということは、今のうちに メンバーシップに 入っていただけるととっても嬉しいです！よろしくお願いします！
So, I'd be very happy if you could join the membership soon! Thank you very much!
さあ、 えーこの後もまだまだ生誕祭続きます！
Now, uh, after this, the 3D live continues!
この後ゲストパートでございます！
After this is the guest part!
ばいばいで グッバイ ばいばいで
Bye-bye, goodbye, bye-bye...
アストロノート 話を聞いてほしいな。
Astronaut, please listen to what I have to say.
君からしたら平穏なことだろうけど
From your perspective, it must seem so ordinary...
メッセージは手書きにしてよ
Make your messages handwritten.
言葉は宙に浮いてしまうから形に残る方が綺麗だから。
Because words float away in the air, leaving them in form is more beautiful.
まだまだいこう 現在の視界は良好
Let's keep going, our current visibility is clear.
自由落下の旅を続けよう
Let's continue our journey of free fall.
ひとりぼっちでヘルツを合わせた二人
Two people all alone who matched their frequencies...
それってしあわせだ
That's what happiness is.
ばいばいで グッバイ ばいばいで いつか会う日まで
Bye-bye, goodbye, bye-bye, until the day we meet again.
それまで残るぼくらの魔法
Until then, our remaining magic.
会いたいの反対の反対 そこが終点だ
The opposite of the opposite of wanting to see you—that's the endpoint.
いまだにぼくら眠っている
We are still fast asleep.
たしたこともないのに 笑ってしまうことがある
Even though it's nothing much, there are times when I find myself smiling.
きっと、そんなんでいいのさ。
I'm sure that's fine just as it is.
別れは青かった。
Our farewells were pale blue.
メッセージは言葉にしてよ
Put your message into words.
キミの声をおぼえていたいから
Because I want to remember your voice.
形のあるものは有限だから。
Because things with physical form are finite.
どこまでいこうかなんて言いながらさ
Saying things like "How far shall we go?"...
ぼくらみな分かっていた 軌道に立ってしまったことを
We all knew it, the fact that we stepped onto this orbit.
ひとりぼっちと分かれ道は似ているけど
Being all alone and a fork in the road look similar, but...
また街で会うから
We'll meet again in the town.
ばいばいで グッバイ ばいばいで すべて群生だ
Bye-bye, goodbye, bye-bye, everything is a colony.
駆け抜けてから思い知った 幼さ。
The childishness I realized only after running through it all.
ばいばいの反対の反対 そこが終点だ
The opposite of the opposite of bye-bye—that's the endpoint.
いずれ、ぼくらにも訪れるだろうから
Because it will surely visit us too eventually.
孤独な旅は続いてく
The lonely journey continues on.
周回軌道で出会えたぼくらははぐれるんだろう
The ones who met on a circular orbit—will we get separated?
声が変わって、背が高くなって、
As our voices changed and we grew taller,
見えるものしか信じなくなっても、
Even if we come to believe only in what we can see,
夢を語るんだろ。
We still talk about our dreams.
中身のない話も素敵だから。
Because even empty conversations are wonderful.
まだまだいこう、ひとりでいこう。
Let's keep going, let's go on alone.
ばいばいで グッバイ Days
Bye-bye, goodbye Days...
ばいばいで グッバイ ばいばいで これでさよならだ
Bye-bye, goodbye, bye-bye, this is farewell.
ついに解けるぼくらの魔法。
Finally, our magic unravels.
会いたいの反対は会いたい それでいいんだよ
The opposite of wanting to see you is wanting to see you—and that's fine.
退屈さえも愛していた。
Even boredom was something I loved.
たしたこともないのに ずっと笑えてしまう日々のこと
The days when we could always laugh over nothing much...
そっとしまっておくのさ。
I'll gently keep them stored away.
ぼくらは青かった。
We were pale blue.
手探りで夢を見る
Fumbling, I see my dream.
何もない ただ信じて
Just believing there's nothing.
宇宙までが遠いほど片道切符を求めて
Seeking a one-way ticket for as far as the sky...
片道切符を求めて
Seeking a one-way ticket,
Wow...
気付いてくれる人がいる
There are people who notice you,
誰も見向きもしなくても
even if no one pays attention.
肩を組んで笑ってきた
Putting our shoulders together and laughing,
僕らはきっと負けない
we surely won't lose.
Wow...
I don't want anything いつだって 今が
I don't want anything, whenever now is
Wow...
常にスタートライン
always the starting line,
Music is everything
遥かなユニバース
a distant universe.
走れ STAR TRAIN
Run, STAR TRAIN!
うーー
Ooh...
線路のない道をゆく
Going down a path without tracks,
想像を超えて進みたい
wanting to advance beyond imagination.
歯車のように噛み合う
Engaging like gears,
力は一人じゃ伝わらない
strength isn't transmitted alone.
Wow...
I don't want anything いつだって 今が
I don't want anything, whenever now is
Wow...
常にスタートライン
always the starting line,
Music is everything
遥かなユニバース
a distant universe.
走れ STAR TRAIN
Run, STAR TRAIN!
Wow...
I don't want anything いつだって 今が
I don't want anything, whenever now is
Wow...
常にスタートライン
always the starting line,
Music is everything
遥かなユニバース
a distant universe.
Wow...
走れ STAR TRAIN
Run, STAR TRAIN!
I don't want anything いつだって 今が
I don't want anything, whenever now is
Wow...
常にスタートライン
always the starting line,
Music is everything
遥かなユニバース
a distant universe.
走れ STAR TRAIN
Run, STAR TRAIN!
Wow...
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ということで、らでん生誕祭2025、ReGLOSSメンバーの5人に来てもらいました！
So, for Raden's Birthday Festival 2025, we invited all 5 ReGLOSS members here!
改めましてになりますが、自己紹介お願いします、青くんから！
To reintroduce ourselves, please give us your self-introductions, starting with Ao-kun!
はい。らでんちゃんちの隣の隣の、ちょっと斜め前くらいに住んでる火威青です、よろしくお願いします。
Yes. I'm Hiodoshi Ao, living next to, next to, slightly diagonally in front of Raden-chan's house. Nice to meet you.
はい、近いの？近いのか？
Yeah, are you close? Are you close by?
らでんちゃんのクラスの隣のクラスの、ちょっと知り合いのクラスメイトとか分からないぐらいの友達な、音乃瀬奏です！
I'm Otonose Kanade, a friend so distant I'm not even sure if we're classmates in the class next to Raden-chan's!
え、どういう感じ？他人？
Huh, what kind of vibe is that? Total strangers?
ええ、らでんの行きつけのお店の、店主の友達の、友達の娘の、幼馴染みのはじめです！
Um, I'm Hajime, the childhood friend of the daughter of a friend of the shopkeeper at Raden's regular spot!
一番遠いかもしれない。
That might be the furthest one yet.
らでんちゃんがよく行くお酒を飲む場所で、
At the place where Raden-chan often goes to drink alcohol...
隣の隣の隣の席に座ってたイチジャリリカでーす！
I'm Ichija Ririka, who sat three seats away!
顔が広い ぜんやんなんか遠いと
You know everyone, Zen-yan seems so far away.
え、というところでございましてね
And with that being said...
えー今回のライブテーマ ここであったのも何かのご縁。やはりね、出会いのご縁といえばこのリグロスのメンバーということで
meeting here must be some kind of bond. As for bonds of meeting, it's about these ReGLOSS members!
やっぱね、一番最初、アワーブライトパレードも5人で歌わせていただきました
After all, right at the start, we also sang "Our Bright Parade" as five people.
楽しかったね！
It was so fun!
楽しかった！楽しかったね！
So fun! It was so fun!
ね、振りもね、こうみんなでね練習してね、覚えたりなんかいたしまして
We all practiced the choreography together, memorized it, and all that!
で、えー今聞いていただいたのは、スタートレインという曲なんですけど、この曲ね、ちょっとね、うふ、みんなですりゃ
And the song you just listened to is called "Start Rain." This song... um, we all...
あの、ラデンが以前からすごく好きな曲でね、歌詞がいいんですよね、いつだってここがスタートレインっていう
Raden has loved this song for a long time, and the lyrics are great, how "right here is always the start rain."
やっぱそれはね、ちょっとリグロスメンバーとも重なる所があったりなんかしちゃって、やっぱ5人で歌いたいなと思って
And that somehow overlaps with us ReGLOSS members, making us want to sing it together as five.
ありがたいことに、そして贅沢なことにですね、このライブでリグロスメンバー5人で歌う曲、2曲出していただけました！ありがとうございます！
Thanks to our gratitude and extravagance, we were given two songs to sing as five ReGLOSS members in this live! Thank you so much!
イェーイ！よくできました！やったー！
Yay! Well done! Yay!
さあ、ということでございまして、もう残すところもあと1曲となりました
Well, with that being said, there's only one song left.
最後ね、ちょっとラデンがしかも1人で生でやるっていうのでちょっとあのめちゃめちゃ緊張してるの
And finally, Raden is doing it live all by herself, so she's super duper nervous!
で、ちょっと一緒に曲振りをしていただいてもよろしいですか？
So, would it be alright if you all joined me in introducing the song?
まっちゃんじゃん！
Here we go!
いきましょう皆さん！
Let's go, everyone!
はい！
Ready!
せーの、どうぞ！
Ready, set, go!
あなたは風のように
Like the wind, you
目を閉じては夕暮れ
close your eyes in the twilight.
何を思っているんだろうか
I wonder what you're thinking.
うー
Ooh...
瞼を開いていた
With your eyelids open,
あなたの目はビイドロ
your eyes are like glass.
少しだけ晴るの匂いがした
There was a faint scent of clearing.
晴れに晴れ、花よ咲け
Clear up, oh flowers, and bloom,
咲いて晴るのせい
blossom for the sake of clearing.
降り止めば雨でさえ
Even if the rain stops,
あなたを飾る晴る
it adorns you with clearing.
胸を打つ音よ蘇生
The sound that strikes the heart, oh calm,
僕ら晴る風
we are the clearing wind.
あの雲も越えてゆけ 遠くまだ遠くまで
Go beyond those clouds, far, still far away.
あなたは晴れ模様に
You, in fair weather,
目を閉じては青色
close your eyes to the blue.
何が悲しいのだろうか
What is making you sad?
瞼を開いている
With your eyelids open,
あなたの目にビイドロ
your eyes are like glass.
今少し雨の匂いがした
Now there's a little scent of rain.
泣きに泣き、空よ泣け
Cry, oh sky, and weep,
泣いて雨のせい
weep because of the rain.
降り頻る雨でさえ
Even in the frequent rain,
雲の上では晴る
above the clouds, it's clearing.
土を打つ音よ鳴れ
The sound of hitting the ground, oh resonate,
僕ら春荒れ
we are the stormy spring.
あの海も越えてゆけ 遠くまだ遠くまで
Crossing over that sea, far, still far away.
通り雨、草を靡かせ
Passing shower, swaying the grass,
羊雲、あれも春のせい
cumulus clouds, also because of spring,
風のように、胸に春乗せ
like the wind, carrying spring on our chests,
春を待つ
waiting for spring.
晴れに晴れ、空よ裂け
Clear up, oh sky, and tear open,
裂いて春のせい
tear open for the sake of spring,
降り止めば雨でさえ
even if the rain stops,
貴方を飾る晴る
it adorns you with clearing,
胸を打つ音奏で
playing the sound that strikes the heart,
僕ら春風
we are the spring breeze,
音に聞く晴るの風
listen to the sound of the clearing wind,
さあこの歌よ鳴れ
now, this song, oh calm!
晴れに晴れ、花よ咲け
Clear up, oh flowers, and bloom,
咲いて晴るのせい
blossom for the sake of spring,
あの雲も越えてゆけ
go beyond those clouds,
遠く、まだ遠くまで
far, still far away.
はーい、ということで最後の曲は
Ha~i, so the final song was
「晴る」聴いていただきました。どうだったでしょうか？
"Haru." How was it?
実は この曲はね、ホロライブデベロップメントの
Actually, this song is also featured on
ReGLOSSのチャンネルでも、5人でカバー動画を出している曲となっております。
the ReGLOSS channel, covered by all 5 members.
聞いたことあるよって方も、
Whether you've heard it before
初耳だよって方も、ぜひ聴いてくれると嬉しいです。
or this is your first time, I'd be so happy if you listen.
晴るありがとうございましたー！
Haru, thank you very much!
それではですね、ここでグッズ紹介をしたいと思うんですが、
Well then, from here, I'd like to introduce some merchandise.
今回のライブ、至る所で二択が出てきましたね。
In this live stream, choices came up at various points.
皆様に色々選んでもらうところを重視したんですが、
We focused on having everyone choose various things,
今回なんとグッズも、2種類、二択があります！
but this time, surprisingly, the merch also has two choices!
ちょっとここグッズたくさんなので、駆け足で行きますよ！まずは、こちら！
There's a lot of merch here, so I'll speed through it! First, this!
はい、こちら「ちょっと一服キャンバスアート」でございます。
Yes, this is the "Chotto Ippuku Canvas Art."
イラストはサムネイルを描いて下さった三月さんなぎ先生です！
The illustration is by Mitsuki Sanagi-sensei!
ね、このレトロな雰囲気いいでしょ？すごくいいと思わない？
Isn't this retro vibe great? Don't you think it's amazing?
この立ててるやつ、これね、昨日のやつあのイーゼルっていうんですが、イーゼルもついてます。お家で飾れます。
This standing thing is called an easel, and it comes with an easel so you can display it.
サイズは15cm×22cmくらいです。
The size is about 15cm x 22cm.
二つ目は、こちら！SNS風アクリルキーホルダー！
Second is this! SNS-style acrylic keychain!
イラストはバカくん三生先生に描いていただきました。
The illustration was drawn by Bakakun Sansei-sensei.
お出かけに行った際に、一緒に写真撮ってSNSで投稿してみてください！
When you go out, try taking a picture with it and posting on SNS!
三つ目は、こちら！らでんのラジオ風ポーチ！
Third is this! Raden's radio-style pouch!
中身が見えるクリア窓となっておりまして、ホロライブフレンズ2号らでんラジオを縦に入れられるサイズ感です。
It features a clear window, sized to vertically fit Hololive Friends #2 Raden Radio.
お次は、こちら！印籠風キーホルダー！
Next is this! Inrō-style keychain!
皆さん印籠ご存知でしょうか？蓋が開閉可能なやつで、「この紋所が目に入らぬか」のやつです。
Do you all know what an inrō is? It opens and closes, like the "Do you recognize this family crest?" one.
中は空洞ですよ。ぜひこの印籠風キーホルダーで、ごっこに使ってください！
The inside is hollow. Please use this inrō-style keychain to play along!
お次はボイス！ASMRボイス「散歩のすすめボイス」台本は自分で考えました！
Next is voice! ASMR voice "Walking Recommendation Voice." I wrote the script!
そしてフルセット購入特典は、直筆サイン入りポストカード！
And the full set purchase bonus is an autographed postcard!
それから特典のASMRボイス「散歩のすすめボイス」が入っております。
And it includes the bonus ASMR voice "Walking Recommendation Voice."
今回サインに関しては無制限ですので、焦らずにご購入いただければと思います。頑張ります！
Autographs are unlimited this time, so please purchase at your own pace. I'll do my best!
さらにフルセット特典として、昨年の...
Furthermore, as a full set bonus, last year's...
9月から販売されました
From September, it's been on sale,
ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが1枚付きます！
and it comes with one card usable in the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME!
カードはホロライブプロダクション公式ショップでご購入された方のみ対象となります。
Cards are exclusively for those who purchased from the hololive production official shop.
特典につくのは推しをアピールできるキーカード「推しホロメンカード」です。
The bonus is a key card to show off your oshi, the "Oshi Holomem Card".
カードの詳細や遊び方についてはホームページにてご確認ください。
Please check the homepage for details on the cards and how to play.
カードは日本語版のみとなりますのでご了承ください。
Please note that the cards are Japanese version only.
と、こちらがですね、誕生日記念グッズだったんですが、さあ2種類というか2択目でございます。それがこちらです、じゃじゃーん！
And, um, these were the birthday commemorative goods, but now we have the second option. Here it is, ta-da!
はい、儒烏風亭らでんきのこダンスグッズフルセットの内容がこんな感じ！1つずつご紹介しますね。まずは、こちらででーん！
Yes, here are the contents of the Juufubuki Raden Kinoko Dance Goods Full Set! I'll introduce them one by one. First, here it is, ta-da!
はい、ぬいぐるみキーホルダーまいたけダンスver.！きのこシリーズのバカくん三世さんのイラストのキーホルダーでございます。まいたけ、まいたけ、ぐるぐるしておりますね！お次はこちらででーん！
Yes, the plush keychain Maitake Dance ver.! It's a keychain with illustrations by Bakakun Sansei. Maitake, maitake, spinning around! Next is this, ta-da!
缶バッジ！こちらもバカくん三世さんのイラスト。こちらあの、ランダムではないです、ランダムじゃないです！いろいろなきのこダンスのショート動画のイラストが缶バッチになりました！まいたけ、しめじ、しいたけ、まつたけ、りんぎの5種類となっております。お次はこちらででーん！
Can badges! These are also illustrations by Bakakun Sansei. These are not random, not random! Various illustrations from the mushroom dance short videos became can badges! There are five types: maitake, shimeji, shiitake, matsutake, and lingzhi. Next is this, ta-da!
マスキングテープ！まいたけダンスのアニメーションをイメージしたマスキングテープ2種類入ってます！これね、搬入のときとか便利です。えー、そしてフルセット購入特典がこちらにもあります。じゃーん！
Masking tape! It includes two types of masking tape inspired by the maitake dance animation! This is handy when transporting goods, etc. Um, and there's also a full set purchase bonus here. Ta-da!
はい、バカくん三世さんのイラストぐるぐるしてるステッカーでございます！
Yes, it's a spinning sticker illustrated by Bakakun Sansei!
という感じで、なんとグッズが同時に2つも出ております！今回ね、みんなにこう選んでいただく楽しみがあったと思うんですが、今回もね、ちょっと自分が好きなほどっちかなってたくさん悩んでください！もちろんね、あのどっちも買うこともできますのでよろしくお願いします！
So, it turns out two goods are released at the same time! I think you all had the fun of choosing, but please worry a lot about which one you like best this time too! Of course, you can buy both, so please look forward to it!
はい、ということで、らでん生誕祭2025いかがでしでしょうか？この日のためにね、もう歌とダンスといっぱい練習してきました！えー、よかったらね、ハッシュタグらでん生誕祭2025で感想をつぶやいてくださるととても嬉しいです！どうかよろしくお願いします！
Yes, so how was Raden's Birthday Festival 2025? For this day, I practiced singing and dancing so much! If you'd like, I'd be very happy if you tweeted your impressions using #RadenBirthdayFestival2025! Thank you very much!
さて、このあとですね、21時30分、21時30分からメンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブもございます！
Now, after this, starting at 21:30, there will also be a membership-limited encore performance!
アンケートで選ばれなかった方の曲も披露させていただきますので、そちらもどうぞよろしくお願いいたします！
I will also perform songs that weren't chosen in the poll, so please look forward to that as well!
えー、ショップはね、21時10分にオープンします。ショップ21時10分オープン、えーアンコールライブが30分からメンゲンであります。よろしくお願いします！
Um, the shop opens at 21:10. Shop opens at 21:10, and the encore performance for members starts at 30 minutes. Thank you!
それでは、あ、もうオープンしたっぽいです！あ、グッズもうオープンしました、すみません！
Well, ah, it looks like it's already open! Ah, the goods are open now, sorry!
えー、それではですね、えー皆さんメンゲンの皆さんはこの後21時30分にまたお会いしましょう！ここででおお別れの方の、えーの見ていただいて本当にありがとうございました！
Well, everyone with membership, let's meet again at 21:30! For those saying goodbye here, thank you so much for watching!
それでは皆さん本日は本当にありがとうございました！それでは、さようならでん！ありがとう！
Well everyone, thank you truly for today! Well then, goodbye-raden! Thank you!